Here's the whole pitch in one screen.
A minute ago, this referral was missing
a required nephrology lab.
Now it's accepted because the app found
that evidence in the chart attached it to the passport
and resubmitted the packet without starting over.
You can literally see the new UACR row,
the checklist turning complete,
and the intake decision flipping from input
required to accepted.
That's Consult Passport.
It is not an AI note writer.
It is a referral acceptance engine
that makes the rules visible.
Repairs what can be repaired,
and keeps an audit trail of every step
between rejection and readiness.
Most referral workflows break on the boring part.
The packet is almost good enough,
one lab is missing, the specialist desk kicks it back,
and suddenly the team is doing phone calls,
chart scavenger hunts, and status updates
in three different places.
What I like about this product is that it treats
that mess as a real workflow problem.
Instead of asking staff to guess what intake wants,
it makes the requirements explicit,
keeps them attached to the run,
and turns the repair path into part of the product.
The workspace starts with real patient context
instead of a blank form.
For this seeded demo, Eleanor Vance already has CKD history,
recent renal labs, medications,
and a referral note in the chart.
The useful thing is that I do not have to manually
repackage that information before I can even ask
for intake review.
I can open the patient record, skim the evidence
that already exists,
and then start a Consult Passport from there.
Under the hood, the app snapshots the FHIR-style context,
assembles the evidence table,
and prepares a structured referral packet
from the chart that is already on hand.
When I submit, the first decision is intentionally strict.
Intake does not just wave the packet through
because the story sounds reasonable.
It evaluates the actual requirements for this destination,
and it tells me one required item is still missing,
a recent UACR.
That is exactly the kind of detail
that usually disappears into email or verbal follow-up.
Here it is explicit, repairable,
and attached to the same live run.
I can see the checklist, the missing rule,
the decision summary, and the button that tells me
there is still a legitimate path to acceptance.
Now watch the part that actually feels different.
I click fetch missing evidence.
The chart tool looks for the latest qualifying UACR,
the run attaches that observation to the evidence table,
and the packet is resubmitted immediately.
There is no fake magic here.
The product is very literal about what changed.
You can see the checklist move from four of five to five of five.
You can see the new UACR row appear in the passport,
and you can see the intake decision flip
to accepted on the same run.
Instead of sending a coordinator on a scavenger hunt,
the system closes the gap with real chart evidence
and shows you the exact before and after.
What makes this more than a flashy demo is the audit trail.
The passport is visible, the evidence is visible,
the intake decision is visible,
and the submission trace shows the exact sequence.
Context bound, snapshot received, packet assembled,
input required, repair started, UACR attached,
resubmitted, accepted.
That matters because referral automation is only useful
if a human can still explain the outcome.
If an intake lead asks why this passed,
there is a concrete answer.
If an engineer asks what the system actually did,
there is a concrete answer there too.
The app is showing both product value
and technical accountability in the same screen.
The system is just as explicit
when it cannot fix the problem.
Marcus Hale follows the same workflow,
but there is not a qualifying UACR in the chart.
The run ends blocked,
not because the app failed silently,
and not because it tried to bluff its way to success.
It reached the limit
of what it could retrieve automatically,
preserved that decision,
and makes the follow-up state obvious.
That honesty is important.
A good demo should show the success path,
but a serious product also has to show
where automation stops.
That's the value here.
Referral intake becomes a deterministic,
inspectable process instead of a black box.
You can show what was submitted,
what was missing, what was repaired,
what still needs manual follow-up,
and when the patient actually became intake-ready.
For a coordinator, that saves time and context switching.
For intake, it improves packet quality
without hiding the rules.
And for judges, it proves this is a real product
with real operational behavior.
The impressive part is not just that it reaches accepted.
It is that every state along the way is visible,
defensible, and grounded in real product interactions.